<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>José Villegas</title>
    <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on José Villegas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 17:26:11 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jose-villegas.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 17:26:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello there! My name is exactly as the site&amp;rsquo;s name, José Villegas. I&amp;rsquo;m a computer science graduate with a minor in computer graphics that has been working for years as game developer. I&amp;rsquo;m originally from Venezuela, Caracas, currently I live in Santiago, Chile. Game development was a natural path for me coming from computer graphics after college as both share many similarities and I really loved games and developing them, I was already making games before I even graduated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get in touch</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 17:26:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>You reach me out using the following:
  Email     LinkedIn     GitHub   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tile&#39;s Waltz - A game born in quarentine</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/tileswaltz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 18:03:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/tileswaltz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tile&amp;rsquo;s Waltz is a game I started developing alone during quarantine for the COVID-19 crisis. It&amp;rsquo;s a puzzle game with a focus on memorization, you remove pieces from the level, when that piece is removed other pieces move to take their place, using this mechanic you need to combine 3 or more pieces of the same color to get combos or powerful power ups. The game still in-development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holly&#39;s Home Design</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/hollys_home_design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/hollys_home_design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Holly&amp;rsquo;s Home Design is a home renovation game developed and published by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gamaga.com/&#34;&gt;Gamaga&lt;/a&gt;. In Holly you play the life of a home renovator, in the game you can buy, renovate, design, decorate and sell houses in different towns. The game features realistic 3D environment and tons of decoration and furniture options.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banana Kong</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/banana_kong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/banana_kong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Banana Kong is another game developed by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gamaga.com/&#34;&gt;Gamaga&lt;/a&gt;, with more than 100M+ of installs, the game is published by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fdg-entertainment.com/&#34;&gt;FDG Entertainment&lt;/a&gt;. Banana Kong is an endless runner platform game, you play as Kong you have to jump, avoid and smash different obstacles in the environment, there are many mechanics that change the way the character moves, it&amp;rsquo;s a really fun game to play.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Crimes : Hidden Murders</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/red_crimes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/red_crimes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Red Crimes is a crime thriller management game developed by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gamaga.com/&#34;&gt;Gamaga&lt;/a&gt; with support of &lt;a href=&#34;www.investigationdiscovery.com&#34;&gt;Investigation Discovery&lt;/a&gt;, sadly the game is no longer supported. The game features realistic crime scenes with multiple game mechanics, focused on hidden objects, investigation, staff mangement and a compelling storyline.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operate Now: Hospital</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/operate_now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/operate_now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I moved to Chile to work with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gamaga.com/&#34;&gt;Gamaga&lt;/a&gt;, I started with Operate Now: Hospital, a game published by &lt;a href=&#34;https://spilgames.com/&#34;&gt;Spil Games&lt;/a&gt; with more than 45M+ of installs. Operate Now is a hospital simulator, in the game you perform really realistic surgeries and follow a compelling storyline, while you also are in charge of running multiple hospitals, upgrading their departments, hiring and managing their staff and many other interesting mechanics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deferred Voxel Shading for Real Time Global Illumination</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/deferred_voxel_shading/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/deferred_voxel_shading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Computing indirect illumination is a challenging and complex problem for real-time rendering in 3D applications. This global illumination approach computes indirect lighting in real time utilizing a simpliﬁed version of the outgoing radiance and the scene stored in voxels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my master thesis for computer graphics, I also published a paper about this technique.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Multi-texture Terrain Rendering</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/terrain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/terrain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a simple implementation of terrain rendering using heighmaps, part of a college assignment. The code has some optimizations such as parallel processing to bake lightmaps and cheap ambient occlusion using the terrain heighmap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volume Rendering with Style Transfer Function</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/styletransfer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/styletransfer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This technique implements style transfer functions for volume rendering, part of a college assignment. Style transfer is extremely convenient for volume rendering as it adds a really great dimension of realism with little overhead. The technique is based on this &lt;a href=&#34;http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.230.9247&amp;amp;rep=rep1&amp;amp;type=pdf&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ollama - A Game In Just A Week</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ollama/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ollama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For this instance I was asked to create a game, alone, in a single week as part of a test. I ended up making an isometric platform game, you have to complete levels and collect coins along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low Poly Water in Unity</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/low_poly_water/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/low_poly_water/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to do a small tests with shaders in Unity to simulate water using sum of sines. This technique is well explained here in &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.nvidia.com/sites/all/modules/custom/gpugems/books/GPUGems/gpugems_ch01.html&#34;&gt;GPU GEMS&lt;/a&gt;. My twist was just using flat shading. The reposity was well received in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jose-villegas/LowPolyWater&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Game Jam 2017 - Echo Switch</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ggj2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ggj2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This time we really wanted to do a co-op game. We built the idea around a platform game where you play with your friend, you both co-perate together to advance in the map and defeat enemies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fur Rendering in Unity</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/fur_unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/fur_unity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a small shader that implements fur rendering in Unity using shell texturing. The technique is well explained on this &lt;a href=&#34;http://hhoppe.com/fur.pdf&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;. Though easy to implement it was well received on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jose-villegas/FurRendering&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spanish Safari</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/spanish_safari/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/spanish_safari/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While I was still in college this was my first experience profesionally as a game developer. Living in Caracas at the time I got contacted by a startup called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.learnsafari.com/&#34;&gt;LearnSafari&lt;/a&gt;, this happened in my last year of college, thanks to the game jams. Spanish Safari is a game or a tool for parents, with the purpose of teaching Spanish to kids in an interactive adventure game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stereoscopy</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/stereoscopic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/stereoscopic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stereoscopy is a technique that enables us to create the illusion of depth for binocular vision. You need special lenses to appreciate the effect. In this college project I implemented a basic rendering engine using C++ with stereoscopy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Game Jam 2016 - Kidz Solution</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ggj2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ggj2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For this game jam we went with a more spooky game. And we wanted to make it multi-player. So we came up with the idea to make a tag game but with some modifications to fit the theme and make it more fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heightmap Generator</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/heightmapgenerator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/heightmapgenerator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A simple height map generator utilizing different noise generation techniques to obtain height maps that can be used for terrain generators or other applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Processing</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/imageprocessing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/imageprocessing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This program implements multiple image processing algorithms, such as edge detection, noise reduction, sharpening etc, part of a college assignment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Game Jam 2015 - Kidz Solution</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ggj2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ggj2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was my first Global Game Jam, though I had been to game jams before in college. This was a really great experience that ended up with me going for four years consecutively. The idea of making a complete game in just 48 hours was first daunting, but later awesome and completely achievable with good team work and focus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Graphics Basic Mapping Techniques</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/firstcg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/firstcg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first started to study computer graphics in my college, this was one of the first assignments, we implemented different real time rendering techniques for this project which included: object selection, translations, rotations and scaling, camera translation and rotation, refraction and reflection, point lights, directional lights, spot lights and shadow mapping.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASCII Filter for WebCam</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/asciiwebcam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/asciiwebcam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This program implements an ASCII art filter for your webcam. This was a small project made during college as an exercise of parallel processing. Getting this effect to run smoothly without parallel processing was impossible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Raytracer</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/simpleraytracer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/simpleraytracer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was an extremely simple raytracer I wrote in college for an assignment. The source code can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jose-villegas/Simple-Raytracer&#34;&gt;here on my GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>