<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gamejams on José Villegas</title>
    <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/tags/gamejams/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gamejams on José Villegas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 10:14:19 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jose-villegas.github.io/tags/gamejams/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bubble Salvage - Global Game Jam 2025</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ggj2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 10:14:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ggj2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After seven years after my last Global Game Jam I went back to it again, this time in completely different country, a different stage of life and completely new strangers, this was an adventure that was worth taking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time we went for a more cozy game with treasure hunt mechanics and exploration as focus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emission - Global Game Jam 2018</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ggj2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ggj2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This game is more competitive we were a bit inspired by the Tron franchise visual style. I was already in Chile when making this game so I worked remotely with my friends in Caracas, Venezuela to complete this game. This game was really fun to play.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Echo Switch - Global Game Jam 2017</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ggj2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ggj2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This time we really wanted to do a co-op game. We built the idea around a platform game where you play with your friend, you both co-perate together to advance in the map and defeat enemies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Haunt - Global Game Jam 2016</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ggj2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ggj2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For this game jam we went with a more spooky game. And we wanted to make it multi-player. So we came up with the idea to make a tag game but with some modifications to fit the theme and make it more fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kidz Solution - Global Game Jam 2015</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ggj2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ggj2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was my first Global Game Jam, though I had been to game jams before in college. This was a really great experience that ended up with me going for four years consecutively. The idea of making a complete game in just 48 hours was first daunting, but later awesome and completely achievable with good team work and focus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>