<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>games on José Villegas</title>
    <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/tags/games/</link>
    <description>Recent content in games on José Villegas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jose-villegas.github.io/tags/games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Game Jam 2018 - Emission</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ggj2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ggj2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This game is more competitive we were a bit inspired by the Tron franchise visual style. I was already in Chile when making this game so I worked remotely with my friends in Caracas, Venezuela to complete this game. This game was really fun to play.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ollama - A Game In Just A Week</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ollama/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ollama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For this instance I was asked to create a game, alone, in a single week as part of a test. I ended up making an isometric platform game, you have to complete levels and collect coins along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Game Jam 2017 - Echo Switch</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ggj2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ggj2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This time we really wanted to do a co-op game. We built the idea around a platform game where you play with your friend, you both co-perate together to advance in the map and defeat enemies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spanish Safari</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/spanish_safari/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/spanish_safari/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While I was still in college this was my first experience profesionally as a game developer. Living in Caracas at the time I got contacted by a startup called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.learnsafari.com/&#34;&gt;LearnSafari&lt;/a&gt;, this happened in my last year of college, thanks to the game jams. Spanish Safari is a game or a tool for parents, with the purpose of teaching Spanish to kids in an interactive adventure game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Game Jam 2016 - Kidz Solution</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ggj2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ggj2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For this game jam we went with a more spooky game. And we wanted to make it multi-player. So we came up with the idea to make a tag game but with some modifications to fit the theme and make it more fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Game Jam 2015 - Kidz Solution</title>
      <link>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ggj2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jose-villegas.github.io/post/ggj2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was my first Global Game Jam, though I had been to game jams before in college. This was a really great experience that ended up with me going for four years consecutively. The idea of making a complete game in just 48 hours was first daunting, but later awesome and completely achievable with good team work and focus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>